Amit Sharma Phone: 9811622011

Email: amitsh4@hotmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A Senior level Professional with over 25 years of experience in Program Management, Customer Management, Leading and managing multi-million dollar international and domestic programs, P&L and implementing various Methodologies to improve delivery efficiency and customer satisfaction. Leading, mentoring and building high productive teams for large scale IT domains including Telecom, Finance, and Project Managers

KEY ACHIEVEMENTS

- Expertise of Project and Program Management, experience in implementing various delivery models and strategies for software products, services and operations
- Managed multi-million dollar international and domestic programs across America, Canada, Europe, Middle East, Latin America and India
- Improve customer satisfaction by 30% over a period of 6 months reflected in improved CSAT scores
- Deliver 10% savings to customer by driving strategic initiatives of Fixed Work package Automation
- Created Sub practice area for CRM from scratch to fully functional team of 25 in span of 4 months
- Extend Business unit Next Generation Networks (NGN) from a team of 4 to 60 in span of 6 months
- Implemented automation first strategy for QA projects reducing time to deliver and improve quality
- Automation of test scripts (Cost saved: \$ 200K; 15000 Man hours per annum)
- Devised new testing processes (Grow additional business by 50%)
- Collation and implementation of Industry Best Practices (Compliance enhanced by 35%)
- Researched & implemented Key Performance Indicators (KPI) for Business units (Reduce cost by 30%)
- Successfully manage bid for OSS Assurance (\$ 8.6M) and Open Call Media Platform (\$ 6.5M), total of \$ 16M in span of 1.5 year

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Technology from National Institute of Technology (NIT), Bhopal 1991-1995

- Certified Project Management Professional (PMP) from PMI
- Certified SCRUM Fundamental from Scrum Study
- Certified Six Sigma White Belt from Six Sigma

TOOLS & TECHNOLOGIES

- OSS Assurance, BSS, CRM (Java, Siebel & MSD), IVR Solutions
- Project Management methodologies Waterfall / Hybrid / Agile Scrum
- MS Office MS Word, MS PowerPoint, MS Excel, Visio, MS Project, JIRA, confluence
- Fair understanding on Cyber Security, ITOM, DevOps, Docker/Kubernetes, SOA, Microservices Arch, Cloud

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Microfocus Software India Private Limited, Gurgaon : Senior Program Manager, Feb 2023 to Till Date (Payroll: Samartha Infosolutions)

- Responsible for project initiation, planning, execution, tracking, managing ongoing challenges
- Create and manage project P&L, Vendor management, Change Management
- Track KPIs, ensure quality and timeliness of project deliveries
- Manage risks, dependencies, anticipate and resolve bottlenecks
- Build rapport with customers and manage them effectively, cross functional team coordination
- Drive status reviews with Customer and internal stakeholders, manage expectations
- Responsible for end to end delivery of Cyber Security & ITOM solutions for Enterprise, Govt. Sector Indian Customers & Middle East customers

COLT Technology Services, Gurgaon : Senior Program Manager, Apr 2022 to Feb 2023 (Payroll: Saksoft Limited)

- Responsible for end to end project deliveries(Plan, estimate and execute), managed project challenges
- Track KPIs, ensure quality and timeliness of project deliveries, drive WSR/MSR
- Manage risks, anticipate and resolve bottlenecks, defect tracking using Azure Devops

- Vendor and internal stakeholders Management, Cross Functional Team Coordination
- Successfully Managed VoIP Monitoring Platform Project used for monitoring different VoIP services for OSS
 & DCN network

TestingXperts Pvt Ltd, Gurgaon: Senior Manager, Aug 2020 to Dec 2021

- Team Management, Resource Planning, Utilization, Performance Management of 30+, distributed team
- Delivered testing project in Offshore/Onshore model as per defined time-line, scope, quality
- Successfully executed Project transition for a US based Client in a short timeframe of 6 weeks
- Collaboration through continuous communication with customer, internal functions and the team
- Interface to key Customer stakeholders Vice-President and Program directors
- Drive weekly/Monthly status reviews, manage customer expectations & escalations
- Successfully Managed -

Project: QA Services for Frontier Communications, USA

Functional, API, Regression testing and development of Automation test scripts for Digital Customer Experience, OSS, Salesforce & Vlocity and Pega Order Entry/ order care using postman and AccelQ tool

Ericsson India Global Services, Gurgaon: Line Manager, Dec 2015 - Dec 2017

- Lead 50+ Multi Location, multifunctional team of BA, Solution Architects and Engineers
- Managed resource planning, utilization, performance, team enablement for delivery
- Resolve and handle potential conflicts within and outside of the team and improve working environment
- Own and Drive delivery of customization, integration and testing projects for global customers
- Ensured quality and timeliness of delivery by tracking KPIs
- Implement industry best practices, contribute proactively to improve the overall working approach
- Partner with stakeholders across multiple teams to create a solid and productive working relationship
- Create communication plan, Managed customer escalations and expectations
- Successfully Managed

Project: BSS Digital Front End Customization, VimpelCom, Ukraine

Delivered customization of front end tools like CSR toolbox, OmniChannel, B2B, B2C, POS, credit decision tool. This includes integration of 3P systems like payment gateway, address validation and Ericsson BSS system using JAVA, Angular Js, Web Services, REST, JSON, Cassandra and Docker

Project: CRM Transformation Project, OPT New Caledonia, ENTEL Chile, Orange Jordon

Delivered implementation of customer management, catalog manager, case management, Knowledge management, dashboard and reporting, order management and CSR toolbox using MS Microsoft Dynamics, ASP.Net, C# and Java

Hewlett Packard India, Gurgaon: Program Manager, Jan 2012 - Oct 2015

- Responsible for project planning & implementation, requirement closure, business Add-On during project delivery and Operation Management post deployment
- Create and Control on Project P&L, budgeting & forecasting, change management
- Risk Analysis and prepare mitigation and contingency planning
- Drive project reviews and negotiate with CXOs and internal stakeholders, Single point of contact (SPOC) for customer issues related to delivery and operations
- Contract negotiation, defining statement of work (SoW) for Vendors
- Contributed as Bid Manager for numerous bids, Proposals, liaison with sales, solution, finance and legal team, obtain approvals from stakeholders as per process guidelines & prepare respective documents
- Successfully Delivered –

Project: OSS Assurance & Inventory Transformation Project for IDEA Cellular, India

Transformation of entire IDEA Cellular Central NOC leveraging HP TeMIP, Inventory Management System, UCA, UTM, Performance Manager, HP Service Manager & UCMDB. The project covers both Transmission and IP network domains. Post roll-out managed O&M in 24x7 support, CRs, SLAs and escalations

Project: OSS Assurance Transformation Project for Indus Towers, India

Transformation of Indus Towers NOC leveraging HP TeMIP, UCA, Large Data Analytic processing in real time leveraging VERTICA. This solution was deployed active-active ready for disaster recovery

Project: IVR Transformation and VAS Modernization solution for IDEA Cellular and Bharti Airtel India

The Solution consist of HP OCMP to support SIP and ISUP for playing audio files to advanced voice-enabled interactive services (VoiceXML & CallControl XML), HP Reporting System to provide statistics and reports

Alcatel Lucent India, Gurgaon: Engineering Manager, Apr 2009 - Jan2012

- Team Management for 60 test engineers, technical leads, Project Managers and SMEs
- Engineering Manager for Test Competence
- Delivered complex testing projects for multiple global clients
- Implement project metrics and update project dashboard, Monitor Quality gates
- Drive Project review and manage escalations, ensure on-time delivery with high quality
- Business development Enhance team skills to attract more business to India business unit
- Successful transition of 6 project work from onsite teams to offshore
- Successfully delivered large enterprise solution in telecom domain
- Next Generation Networks (Call Session Controller), VoIP project
- Service Management Center, Media Gateway Controller (MGC)
- IMS Domain Access Gateway Control Function (3G)
- Enhanced Subscription Location Server, Application Enablement (JAVA domain)

Alcatel Lucent India, Gurgaon: Team Leader, Jul 2006 - Mar 2009

- Lead team of 24 resources to deliver testing projects, manage E2E STLC and test labs
- Automation of test activities to enhanced productivity of team, drives innovation by introducing new tools

Alcatel Lucent India, Chennai: Test Project Leader, Jun 2003 to Jun 2006

- Worked as Global Project Leader in Milan, Italy for pre-integration and integration testing for E2E solution
- Responsible for all test activities and defining test strategies, plan, reports and other project documents

Alcatel Italia S.p.A, Milan, Italy: Senior Engineer, Apr 1998 - May 2003

 Prepare and execute test plans for UAT, SIT and load testing for switching software, troubleshoot software faults, software upgrade and testing, Testing of SS7/ISUP signaling at Alcatel R&D Center, Milan, Italy for 2.5 years, support ALBTELECOM, Albania for 1.8 years, NITEL Nigeria for 6 months, Airtel, India for 4 months

Early Part of Career

Permali Wallace Ltd, Bhopal: Software Engineer, Aug 1997 - Apr 1998 RPG Satellite Communication Ltd, Bhopal: Software Engineer, Nov 1995 - Mar 1997

TRAININGS

- Managerial Skill Training Harvard Manage Mentor (HMM) Program
- Attended JUMP Management Program for Leadership
- Participated in Organizational Transformation 4 Key Behavior Workshop
- M-Power certification for Management skills
- Completed Advanced Excel and VBA Scripting Training
- Completed RCA, Estimation Techniques Training
- CloudU Certification